GEORGIOS E. MAGDIS

Associate Professor - Cosmic DAWN Center

Niels Bohr Institute / University of Copenhagen (NBI/KU) Danish Space Institute / Danish Technical University (DTU-Space)

email: georgios.magdis@nbi.ku.dk Tel: +45-53775257

web: http://www.georgiosmagdis.com/ ORCID: https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4872-2294

RESEARCH PROFILE

I am an Associate Professor of extragalactic astrophysics and co-founder of the Cosmic DAWN Center (DAWN) at the Niels Bohr Institute/University of Copenhagen (NBI/KU) and the Danish Space Institute/Technical University of Denmark (DTU-Space). I am leading the ISM/galaxy-evolution group at DAWN (3 MSc, 3 PhD and 1 post-Doc) funded by my research grant "Gas to stars - Stars to Dust; Exploring the Star Formation Activity Through Cosmic Time" (€950k). I focus on the study of galaxies across cosmic time aiming to shed light on their formation, their growth, and the evolution of their interstellar medium. For my research I use space and ground-based deep multi-wavelength cosmological surveys with an emphasis on infrared/submm/radio observations. As of 2019 I am also co-ordinating the high redshift science case for the SPICA space telescope and I am a member of the Euclid "Primeval Universe Working Group".

EDUCATION

University of Oxford, UK

DPhil in Astrophysics

University of Crete, GR

MSc in Astrophysics

University of Crete, GR

September 2005

September 2003

BSc in Physics

ACADEMIC POSITIONS

Cosmic Dawn Center, DTU-Space and NBI/KU, DK

Associate Professor - Co-founder

Dark Cosmology Center, NBI/KU, DK

Assistant Professor - Carlsberg Fellow

University of Oxford, UK

Post-doctoral Researcher

Service d'Astrophysique, CEA, Saclay, FR

Post-doctoral Researcher

November 2015 - April 2018

April 2012 - November 2015

November 2009 - April 2012

Post-doctoral Researcher

GRANTS/FUNDING

Centers of Excellence, DNRF €8.5million (co-founder/core member)	2018 - 2024
Cosmic Dawn Center of Excellence	
Young Investigator Program, Villum Foundation, €950k (PI)	2016 - 2021
Gas to stars - Stars to Dust; Exploring the star formation activity through cosmic time	
DARK/Carlsberg Independent Research Fellowship €350k (PI)	2015 - 2018
THALES Programme, €521k (co-I)	2012 - 2015
The invisible side of formation and evolution of supermassive Black Holes in the Univers	e
Astrophysical Data Analysis Program, NASA, \$116k (co-I)	2012
Extreme silicate absorbers in WISE	

PUBLICATIONS

136 (69 since 2014) peer reviewed publications in high profile journals (3 in Nature), 14 as a first author. Citations: ~ 12500 (9500), h-index: 58 (50) - Google Scholar (NASA/ADS).

SUPERVISION

Master Students (7) (2 ongoing)

S. Ponchida , A. Anastasiou, E. Paspaliaris, Cecilie Sand Norholm, C. Sand Norholm, I. Cortzen, M. Papathanasiou

PhD Students (4) (3 ongoing)

V. Kokorev, I. Cortzen, S. Manning (co), C. Gomez Guijarro (co)

Post-Docs (3) (1 ongoing)

F. Valentino, I., L. Ciesla (co), N. Lee (co)

TELESCOPE TIME ALLOCATION

In total for my research I have been awarded >1500hours (as PI or co-I) of observing time in the most competitive ground-based and space telescopes (including ALMA, NOEMA, IRAM 30m telescope, APEX, Herschel, Spitzer, HST, VLT and Keck).

MAIN INTERNATIONAL COLLABORATIONS AND PROJECTS

Major International Collaborations

University of Oxford (UK)* Caltech (USA)* Center for Astrophysics (CfA/Harvard, USA) * CEA/Sacley (Paris, France) * Max Plank Institute for Extra-terrestrial Physics (MPE, Germany) * National Optical Astronomy Observatory (NOAO, USA)* ESO (Germany)

Major International Projects/Teams

ALCS * REQUIEM* BUFFALO * PEP * GOODS * GOODS-Herschel * GOODS-ALMA * HerMES * CLS * KROSS * COSMOS* Candels-Herschel * Cosmic Dawn Survey * SPICA * Euclid

INTERNATIONAL RECOGNITION AND AWARDS - SELECTED

Enhanced Eurotalents, Proposal Reviewer	2017
NASA Astrophysical Data Analysis Program, Selection Committee	2017
ESO, Time Allocation Committee	2017-2018
ERC Starting Grant, Proposal Referee	2016
Royal Astronomical Society Group Achievement Award	2014
32 Invited/Contributed Talks / 7 Colloquia	2010 - $present$

PRESS RELEASES AND OUTREACH - SELECTED

2019
~010
2017
- 2015
2014
2014
2012
2011
2011
•